hey what's up everybody thanks for
listening to The Grow Your Life
podcast I'm trying something brand new
tonight that I've never done before
where I'm just going to I'm in the deep
end of my pool and I'm just going to
Wade water while I do the podcast I
think this is like a cool approach um on
here so anyways thanks for being here
what I want to talk about is dealing
with negativity and how as a coach and
Mentor you deal with negativity it comes
in different formats um I probably won't
look at the camera by the way and so if
you're again if you're watching video
you can see me kind of just like waiting
up and
down in the pool similarly to like if
I'm on a treadmill or something like
that um but anyways yeah negativity in
your coaching business here's the truth
you're going to deal with it no matter
how much Integrity you
have not necessarily your own negativity
but from other people coming at you and
so how do you deal with especially like
a toxic response or people being really
rude or negative with you and how do you
deal with it when it comes from a
stranger on social
media and then how do you deal with it
when it comes from a paid client okay
and so this is kind of uh a topic it's
come up a few times in our group dealing
with people that are disappointed I talk
about one of the number one things that
you need to do to be more financially
successful as a coach and Mentor is
become okay
with some people being disappointed in
you some people not liking what you're
putting out there um people not
resonating with it and some
people their
anger and insecurity and things that
they're dealing with themselves
manifests in hurling negativity at you
um usually unsolicited and things like
that I've had a lot of negativity
sometimes gotten called a scammer uh
saying that I I've never succeeded have
made up all of my track record nothing
that we've ever done exists that we have
the worst offers by the way these aren't
ever people that have actually bought
anything or attended any of our webinars
or ever gone through any of my podcast
episodes or are any of our incredible
clients that we have in our coaching
program at all these are just
Rando people that see our offer on
social media and assume what it is or
like somebody's like you know you just
learned this in a Russell Brunson book
last night and you're trying to pass off
as a fake Guru with a fake income that's
never done anything to help anybody and
I'm just like my gosh we've
generated millions of dollars in sales
for our business our clients have
we have some of the best success stories
ever uh I think we have the best
coaching program ever for people if
they're a coach Mentor trainer author
and they want to get more clients online
with Facebook ads is that's what we
specifically focus on almost
exclusively um but then I do teaching in
the podcast about things like mindset
and things that coaches and mentors deal
with and we give away a lot of
incredible really really great free
content around that so anyways the
negativity will increase the more
success you
have
which is like a chicken and egg scenario
cuz a lot of people think that once I
have success once I have a certain level
of success people will trust me more and
that's true some people will the ones
who are meant to work with you will but
there will also be doubters haters
people that say that oh you've never
done that or you can't do that and we
know that
success in business especially in
coaching manifests in a very unique
way um that isn't always tangible isn't
always monetary isn't always what you
can show but it can be the internal work
right and so that's
where sometimes people have trouble with
connecting that and then if you're
selling that for like 3,000 5,000
$10,000 people think that
okay this is a scam it's unethical
things like that so there's those that
believe this there's there's a brand new
uh documentary on
Netflix all about uh what is it the
twinflame I guess sort of cult uh
coaching program I don't know um and it
was a coaching program that uses the
same type of marketing that we do the
same methodologies for getting clients
but they're it's an expose on Netflix
about them being abusive to people and
causing all these problems and all these
different things
and so that gets in people's heads to
where they think that you know that's
what all coaches are that's what all
mentors are and that people that do this
for a living are all scammers or they're
all abusive or they're all this or
they're all that and and then that's one
of the things that I see that a lot of
people when they come and work with me
they get stuck
on is the judgments that they have
towards other people so the negativity
comes because espe a lot of coaches a
lot of mentors a lot of people who get
coaching are also very
judgmental of other people they're very
harshly critical of all the things that
they're
doing and so
inherently um it becomes you attract
negativity when you go out there as a
coach mentor and you're promising a
dream transformation to people you're
promising to create a massive result in
their life that
that it would attract some negativity
from people who don't believe that it
would work for them or that it that
don't believe that it would turn out
well for them okay and so these people
become very negative because their
worldview and their narrative and what
their story is they have to validate it
to feel okay they have to validate by
hurling anger
negativity demonizing villainizing
threatening you know actual threats from
people verbally they'll never act on it
they'll never do it but they'll they'll
get verbal so the more success you have
the more this happens that's one of the
funny things about it especially in the
coaching and digital course business is
that the more success you have the more
resistance of people trying to stop you
of people trying to discredit you of
people you know not believing you and
yet at the same time
your bank account is growing you're
making a ton of money you're having
success you're impacting lives you're
changing people's
lives all over the
world and your clients love you you have
incredible testimonies and stuff that so
that's where you know we've hit in our
business and I've gotten to the point
now where it doesn't bother me I don't
have to validate myself to anybody who
does that I don't have to prove to them
that oh I'm right and they're wrong and
stuff like that even if they're
believing lies I don't have to manage my
reputation tightly and and we have an
incredible reputation with our clients
they love working with us the results
that we produce is
incredible but there are people who are
going to
assume based on however they
filter what you're doing or what you're
saying through their lens of
understanding and they have to verbally
blast you and try to hurt you with
negativity okay so that happens it has
more to do with them than anything to do
with you so don't worry about it let it
go don't defend yourself just let it go
let them think whatever they want you're
not going to prove yourself to them
you're not going to change their mind
that's the crazy part about it like I
had somebody tonight on my social media
telling me all these negative things
that I have no results my income is made
up that I'm a fake Guru that I my offers
are terrible he's
never bought anything for me I'm not
going to somehow I'm not going to send
him this podcast episode and be like hey
look I made a podcast about your
negativity you know did I did I feel
tempted to do that sure maybe but that's
a stupid idea cuz cuz that's only going
to further fuel their attention
addiction and that's really what they
want those people that are super
negative that try to hurl all that
negativity at you they just want
attention they just want your attention
and so when you give it to them it fuels
it and it gets worse and worse and worse
and then they sort of feed off of it
like a vampire of your energy from the
negativity and so you diffuse it by
simply not engaging if they were
accusing you of something I had somebody
accusing me of like criminal activity
defrauding people stuff like that I will
say that is not true it's not accurate
we've never done that and I'll speak the
truth so I I'll go on record with the
truth but I'm not going to try to prove
it to them you know cuz they'll always
need the last laugh and they'll always
need the last rebuttal to where they're
the last one saying
something
and because of
that um they'll usually come back with
something super negative after you say
that that's usually that's usually where
you can you can end the conversation and
not continue I'll usually always reply
back if somebody's being really negative
and nasty and then I end the
conversation
there um and so there's that just learn
to especially like if you're getting
started you might have self-doubt I had
an incredible track record generating
eight figures in
business multiple times
over for the last 20 years and yet had a
lot of security and impostor syndrome
because I had people being negative to
me and there was a lot of unhealed
trauma internally I had this belief that
if people are harshly critical of me
that I have to prove them to prove
what's right and to defend myself
and now I don't have to and so when I
kind of and I worked through that with
my therapist that was a big thing that I
actually worked through in
therapy was to where that didn't affect
me and I it used to completely destroy
me where I would be like somebody would
be super negative at me and I would be
on the couch for
weeks and couldn't like think
straight
now I couldn't care less at
all now it gets a little bit harder when
they are a paid client when they have
come in when they have really gone
through your stuff cuz if somebody has
never engaged with you done business
with you they're just prejudging a book
by its cover oh my gosh like not even
worth your time of day to engage with at
all it's laughable like literally you
just laugh it
off when they're a
client that can get a little bit
trickier and that's where we do need to
take on a little bit of personal
responsibility as
to how how did we attract this client
how did we bring them in because if that
person is perpetually getting
negative um one way that this could be
is there's people that they will desire
power and they'll give you
referrals and they will demand more of
you than you're willing to give and then
get really angry at you and start
hurling negativity when you don't do
what they
want
and they become clients I've had this
happen especially in the coaching space
especially in the digital course space
because a lot of people think that
control is how you have
success self-control is controlling your
own thoughts is but not controlling
other
people and so I've had this happen and
they've come in my
program this is why I have a 30-day
money back guarantee because they
usually take me up on it
like the fact that we
guarantee
everything uh for 30 days is like it's
incredible you
know
um and I had somebody do this recently
and they sent me a really negative nasty
email back just about
how I basically I'm a horrible coach and
teacher and my content was no value to
them that I just suck and should just
stop being in business and that I have
no right being in business and doing
what I do and it actually did bother me
for a couple of days it really
did till I realized wow if I took this
person's advice I'd be as broke as they
are and they're very broke in their
business they're not making a lot of
money that's why they came to me in the
first place and then this this person
also like had told me you know every
coach I work with has screwed me over
playing the victim so if you've noticed
people are playing the
victim up
front neighbors got their dogs out if
you notice somebody's playing the victim
up
front that's somebody to like
really not engage with not worry about
not worry about what they think
um that's somebody that you don't want
in your ecosystem that's somebody that
you
don't want in your coaching you want to
that's a red flag pay attention to red
flags that you allow allow around you
and listen if you grew up like I did
around everybody who was basically a
Perpetual red flag they'll be familiar
to you and your own validation you might
be trying to even validate yourself I'm
going to move over here you might be
trying to validate yourself and even
certain things from your
childhood
that hasn't been resolved
yet with these people because the your
caregivers maybe were super negative
growing up or
you you had a sister or a brother or an
uncle and you were you're basically
trying to resolve the lack of love in
those situations with clients that act
in a similar way that's again something
that I was doing I was attracting
manipul of narcissistic covert
narcissistic men who are like my
um uh My adoptive SL
stepdad
and like trying to literally resolve my
childhood trauma with coaching clients
and this is something if you're not
aware of you're like that you'll end up
doing and that's why we can end up
attracting people that are not good for
us in our
programs and so listen you want to have
a boundary it's not rude to not tolerate
certain people acting a certain way
sometimes it can be tempting too
especially if they want to give you
referrals here's what you'll usually
find some of the most negative people
usually offer up
referrals it's a very interesting thing
so be cautious
about like accepting
favors from certain people because when
they come to collect those
favors they can get very
negative around that okay so that's
where a become self-aware of how did I
attract these people how did I bring
them into my life how did they come in
how can I make sure to repel those
people in the future and then literally
you want to like cut them out of your
life you don't want to try to resolve it
you don't want to try to make it better
you don't want to do that you want them
gone these are people that drain you
that are very negative that are very
rude that are very disrespectful you do
not need to tolerate being around them
okay but when they're a paid client or
there're somebody who is in your inner
circle or your friends or even somebody
at church that can be hard sometimes
it's best to just
ignore do your own thing and let them go
out of your life and I've had to do that
before and I've had people people when
I've do done that be very nasty at me
back accuse me of just horrible
things that never happened or
anything and I just let let them go I
don't need them to think different than
me I'm going to be the bigger person to
walk away from this and so that's what I
just would really recommend when dealing
with negativity is to have a boundary in
your life to where you don't tolerate it
you don't tolerate it in media you don't
tolerate it from family from friends and
even say that hey you're being really
negative right now hey you're being
really rude right now my wife and I
actually are willing to say that to each
other if we think the other person is
being negative or rude and it helps snap
us out of oh wait you're right something
is off if somebody's being negative
something is off in their life so don't
let them affect you and in your own
effort to avoid them don't avoid attra
like putting yourself into situations
where they might be because as you grow
the more people you impact the you will
have them coming around you they will
try to get in does that make
sense so it's not a bad thing that if
they're trying to get in I think that's
something to uh that's a big unlock for
some of y'all is that you think oh if
these negative people are coming in
that's something I should avoid actually
it might be an area for you to lean into
more of but learn to strengthen yourself
to where you can have boundaries and it
doesn't bother you like it used to
that's what I've had to do in my
business and it has helped me grow by
instead of me trying to just run away
from the negative people I put myself
into where they
are I allow them to be how they
are but I become really irresistible and
incredible to a very small subset of
people that will actually become my paid
clients and so that's a good thing to do
this is why we need to resolve our
trauma we need to calm our internal
nervous system
down and we will be able to attract the
clients that are best to work with us
okay all right I think this has been
great I think this has been a great
teaching I think that that last unlock
right there is going to really impact
some of you all in a positive way and so
grow your life everybody we'll talk soon
have a good
one
[Applause]
[Music]